[police radio calls]
Get back!
I'll kill her!
Oh, my god!
3-l-90. I repeat 3-l-90.
Request you notify
hostage negotiation team.
Have them respond--
Officer:
Petersen!
Suspect: Get your boys
out of here.
Officer: Suspect, male,
caucasian, approximate--
I'm a reporter.
I'm with the press,
How long have
you guys been here?
Get out of here!
Is this domestic
or drugs?
Is that
his girlfriend
Or what?
Get out of here!
Who is it?
Come on,
talk to me.
Masius,
please get him
Out of here.
Walk!
Come on.
I got my passes, masius.
Shit!
Hey! I got
every right
To be here.
Where'd he go?
Officer: Suspect
has withdrawn
Into the interior
of the room.
We no longer
have visual contact.
Aah!
No!
That was my...Car.
That was--
Ohh!
Ooh.
Aw.
Having a little
car trouble?
That's a keen
observation.
I can help you.
It's the jag.
You want me
to drive home
In your car?
No. I want you
to take my car.
Had a lot of luck lately.
I don't need it.
You're giving me
a brand-new jaguar,
And you don't
want anything?
Well, I can prove it.
Give me your card.
[grrr]
I'll be in touch.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
What is this?
What--what?
Do you want me
To kill your wife
or something?
No. Tempting, but, no.
Call it generosity
between 2 strangers.
Generosity? Hey, fella,
it's a jaguar.
You expect me
to drive off
In a brand-new jaguar,
and that's it?
That's right.
Hey! You're a freak.
You know that?
You are a freak.
You want me
to get in this car?
No way. It's probably
going to blow up.
Yeah. That's real funny.
Bits and pieces of me
raining down
In the street.
Ha ha. You think
I'm going near
that thing? You're nuts!
Besides, I've got a car.
Sort of.
[hip-hop music playing]
[pop music playing]
What?
You like it?
Cool blade, huh?
Want to see
your guts--
Keep it in your pants.
Fag.
He's going
to kill you.
I got pepper spray.
[class bell rings]
[students chatting]
[class falls silent]
Apparently none of you
have ever seen
A new teacher before.
I'm mr. Simonet.
Welcome to the seventh
grade, middle school--
That hellish,
shaky bridge
You all must cross
before you become
Members of
that undyingly enviable
High-school elite.
Now, some of you might
think you can't get
Across this bridge
fast enough,
That you'd rather
hold your breath,
Close your eyes,
and not think
About anything
until it's all over.
Well, I'm here
to tell you
That that is not
an option in this class.
[students laugh]
Lateness--
Busted.
Tardiness--
To be late
for your first class
On your first day
of school,
What does that indicate?
I'm having
a bad hair day.
[students laugh]
Perhaps
what it indicates
Is a lack of respect.
You see, I'm going
to be here every day
For you.
And so, I expect you
to be here for me.
On time. No excuses.
Put that down.
[whispering]
wait.
Now...
This class is
social studies.
That is you
and the world.
Yes, there is
a world out there,
And even if you decide
you don't want
To meet it,
it's still
Going to hit you
right in the face.
Believe me.
So, best you start
thinking about
The world now
And what it means
to you.
What does the world
mean to you?
Come on! A little class
participation here.
Is it just this class
you want to get out of?
Your house? Your street?
Any further any of you
want to go than that?
Yes.
The mall.
That's only,
Like, 2 miles
away from me.
Well, let me ask you
another question.
How often do you
think about things
That happen outside
of this town?
You watch the news? Yes?
No?
All right. So we're
not global thinkers yet,
But why aren't we?
'cause we're 11.
Good point.
What's your name?
Trevor.
Maybe trevor's
absolutely right.
Why should we think
about the world?
I mean, after all,
what does the world
Expect of us?
Expect?
Mm-mmm. Of you.
Mr. Simonet: What does
the world expect of you?
Nothing.
My god, boys and girls,
he's absolutely right.
Nothing.
I mean, here you are.
You can't drive.
You can't vote. You can't
even go to the bathroom
Without a pass from me.
You're stuck!
Right here,
in the seventh grade.
But not forever.
Because one day,
you'll be free.
[students cheering]
All right. But what if
on that day you're free,
You haven't prepared,
you're not ready,
And then
you look around you
And you don't like
what the world is?
What if the world...
Is just
a big disappointment?
We're screwed.
Unless--
Unless you take the things
that you don't like
About this world and
you flip them upside down
Right on their ass--
don't tell your parents
I used that word--
and you can start that...
Today!
This is
your assignment.
Extra credit.
It goes on
all year long.
[students groan]
Now, wait a minute.
What?
What? What's wrong
with this?
What's the matter?
Yes?
It's--it's, like, so--
So what? There must
be a word to finish
That sentence.
Someone help her?
Weird.
Crazy.
Hard.
Bummer.
Bummer. Hard.
How about possible?
It's possible.
The realm of possibility
Exists where
In each of you?
[whispering] here.
So you can do it.
You can surprise us.
It's up to you.
Or you can
just sit back
And let it atrophy.
Atrophy.
If there is
a word you hear
That you don't
understand,
There's a dictionary
at the front of the room.
Look it up.
And there are
these dictionaries,
Which you will carry
with you at all times,
Because in this class,
we're going to learn
To love words
and their meanings.
Any questions?
Trevor: Yeah.
So you'll,
like, flunk us
If we
don't change
The world?
Well, no.
I wouldn't do that.
But you might just
squeak by with a "c."
What'd you ever do
to change the world?
Students: Whoa!
Well, trevor, I get
a good night's sleep,
I eat a hearty
breakfast,
I show up on time,
And then I pass
the buck to you.
Now, I want you all
to write your names
In these books,
and--what's your name?
Molly? All right.
I want molly to look up
the word "atrophy."
[dance music playing]
No, we're not coming
down to milwaukee.
No. You went
straight to hell.
Straight to hell.
Ok. 4 tequilas.
Who's having
The fourth one?
You are.
Oh, no, no.
Not for me.
Thank you.
You cannot
get in trouble.
We bought it
for you.
I thank you
so much.
No, thank you.
Oh, come on.
Why not?
Because
I promised my kid.
Men: Ohhh.
I know. It's horrible!
You guys have fun!
Wait, wait.
Here. Here.
Thank you.
Ohh! Uh-oh.
What are you doing,
junior?
What is junior
gonna do?
Uh-oh. What are
you doing, junior?!
What are you
doing?!
What time
do you get off?
If only
I weren't married!
Oh, no.
Aww. She's married.
She's married.
I'm single!
I'm single! Whoo!
[telephone rings]
[ring]
Hello.
Woman: Hey!
Hey.
How'd it go?
Are you there?
Yeah.
How'd it go?
What?
How was
your first day?
Ok.
Trev, come on,
you got to speak up.
I can't hear you, ok?
Ok.
Sorry I wasn't home.
I had a chance
To pick up
another shift,
So you know I didn't
have a choice.
You mad at me?
So, trev,
what're you doing?
Nothing.
You find
the spaghetti?
I'm eating it.
Mom: Good.
Come on, honey, tell
me what happened.
I got to go.
A spoon?
Spoon?
[gasps]
Mom.
Mom!
Mm-mmm. Mm-mmm.
My friend's coming in
to take a shower, ok?
Ok.
That's not
really breakfast.
You don't eat breakfast.
Well, let's have some.
Come on.
I'll make some eggs.
I'll have some, too.
You sure
you won't throw up?
What is that
supposed to mean?
What do you think
it means?
Why don't you tell me
what it means.
You're sneaking it.
I'm not sneaking anything.
Ok!
Trevor.
Trevor,
wait a minute.
I'm sorry.
You're right.
Listen.
Sit down
for one minute.
I want
to talk to you.
You wanna lie to me.
No. I don't want
to lie to you.
I want you to sit
down for one minute.
Hey! I want us
to get along.
Aah!
Sorry.
It's ok, mom.
...Find
the toilet paper.
Who are you?
You get out!
Ok.
Get out of my house!
Thanks a lot.
Mom: I said what?
Get out!
Man:
No. I got it.
You said
he could come in
And take a shower.
I never said that!
Yes, you did!
You said--
I said it's ok
to let a strange man
Into my bathroom?
He's my friend.
What? You can't
have a friend like that.
It's for
my assignment.
What assignment?
You won't get it.
Mr. Simonet
will get it.
Who's mr. Simonet?
Hey!
I'm talking to you.
He's my teacher!
[school bell rings]
Mr. Simonet?
Yes. I'm eugene...
Uh, simonet.
Hello.
What is
this assignment?
'scuse me?
What did you tell
my son to make him
Bring a homeless man
into my house?
Uh, I have 2 problems.
One, I have absolutely no idea
what you're talking about.
And 2, I don't know
who you are.
Arlene mckinney.
My boy is
In your social studies
class? Trevor.
Trevor.
Yes, he's very attentive.
He's very exigent,
Which I like.
Exigent.
It's challenging,
testing--
I know
what it means.
Would you
like to tell me why
My kid brought a bum
into my house.
I have no idea.
Bullshit!
Mrs. Mckinney,
I don't know
How your son interpreted
the assignment.
How do you think
he interpreted it?
Well, I don't know.
My suggestion to you is
if you want to know,
Why don't you go home
and talk to your son.
Hey!
I talked to him.
Really?
Then why did you come
All the way down here
to ask me
What the assignment is?
It's not a state secret.
Yeah! And?
It's an assignment
I give out
At the beginning
of every year to inspire.
I don't expect them
To actually change
the world, the whole--
You expect them
to change the--
Excuse me.
It's to get them to think,
Not walk on water.
It's a very good assignment.
You give them
an assignment
You don't think
they can do.
What kind of teacher
are you?
I didn't say that.
You know, they make attempts.
Every now and then, they
clean up a little graffiti
Before
they lose interest.
Hey! This is my kid!
You don't know him.
You tell him
he can do something,
He's going
to believe you.
And when he can't,
It's going
to wipe him out.
They ought
to fire your ass
Out of here
right now!
Well, you know,
they probably won't do that,
Because I fill
a very excellent quota.
I'm just this side
of parking in the blue zone.
Oh, so you think
You can do
whatever you want
Just 'cause
your face is messed up?
Mrs. Mckinney, why don't you
put down in writing
Your little and loud complaints,
and I'll make sure
They get put
in the suggestion box.
Jesus.
You are
really somethin'.
Thanks. I appreciate
the euphemism.
I've always wanted
to be somethin'.
Man: Can I help you
with something, miss?
Oh. Uh, no.
Mr. Thorsen! Hey!
Hey, hold up, man.
Come on,
I've been waiting
all day for you.
Hey. Hey, why won't
you return my calls?
We're not friends.
You know, I got
the pink slip for the car,
And that's quite
a stocking stuffer.
Are you gonna tell me
you can't accept it?
No, no. That would
make me a moron.
I just want to know
about these,
Uh, these instructions
you left me.
Just do what they say.
Pay it forward.
Why?
Because you've
accepted the car.
You're obligated.
I'm obligated.
Well, what if I don't
feel obligated, huh?
Well, what if I
just take my new car
And get a couple hookers
And drive down
to mexico?
I'll never know.
But you'll what--
what is this?
Come on, for real.
An attack
of total altruism
From a litigator.
I've got a meeting.
I've got a story, ok?
A senior partner
at channing and moss
Is giving away new cars?
You could tell me a reason,
or I could make one up.
Mine will be a lot more
interesting, I promise.
You've gone dotty.
You're wearing crystals.
You're keeping a few
too many cats at home, huh?
All right. Look, all right?
Listen. Listen, please.
My ex-wife has
everything, ok? There.
Plus she's
in a lesbian relationship,
I think,
just to piss me off.
Help me out, please.
My daughter has asthma.
One night, it was very bad,
The worst I'd ever seen it.
It was the middle
of the night,
The emergency room.
We were waiting forever.
Couldn't get anyone
to pay attention.
[man laughing]
Her inhaler doesn't
seem to be working at all.
Sorry. Mr. Parker.
What happened?
My sister,
she stabbed me.
I can't believe--
Excuse me.
We were here first.
I'm sorry, we have to go
with stab wounds first.
She can't breathe.
She's very scared.
Look,
I will let you know.
Mr. Thorsen:
Somebody has to see her.
Nurse: I'm sorry.
It's protocol.
It's never been
this bad.
You have
to do something.
Sir, would you
just sit down?
I'm sorry. We've
been here for 4 hours.
You need
to get a doctor.
No. No, wait.
Hey, no. No!
Would you excuse me?
Excuse me.
That's bullshit. You need
to help her right now!
Excuse me?
No. No, why you give
me all this shit?
Ain't you got
some oxygen
Or something
you can give her?
Fine, let me--
no, no, no.
You don't need
to get no supervisor.
You're the supervisor
of the day. Huh?
You are
the supervisor today.
You feel me on that?
Now, I want you to take
Your skinny ass
down the hall,
Put the little girl
on a tray, and supervise her,
And I want you to get her
some goddamn air!
I got your back, sis.
Oh, bitch, you still here?!
Shit!
[gunshots]
Oh, shit ain't funny,
now, is it?
Come on, man! No! No, man!
This ain't fair, man!
Come on! Come on, man!
There! There!
Mr. Thorsen:
I thanked him,
And there were some
very specific orifices
In which I was told
to shove my thanks.
He told me,
"just pay it forward."
3 big favors
for 3 other people.
That's it.
So, it's like
a "pass it on" thing, then.
Wait a minute.
You and this lowlife
Were in this chain
of do-gooders?
Some kind of mother teresa
conga line?
That's a little new agey
for you, isn't it?
Sort of tibetan?
What, are you
in a cult?
If you mention
my name,
You'll be
selling your kidneys
To pay
for your lawsuit.
Cult.
Hey. The guy--
What was
the guy's name?
Sorry. I'm late
for my mass wedding.
[door squeaks]
[gasps]
Hey!
I know
somebody's in here.
[clatter]
man: Oh.
Arlene:
I know you're there.
I want you to come out,
Or I will find you
and shoot you, I swear--
Please don't shoot.
Please.
You stay right there.
If I see you move one--
[screams]
[rifle fires]
Please don't
pick it up!
Please don't.
I'm not moving.
Please.
What are you doin'
on my truck?
Let me show you.
I'm just--
I'm just gonna
open the door, ok?
[engine starts]
See, it might be easier
for you to sell now...
Now that it works.
I didn't ask
for your help.
No.
You been living
in my garage?
No. Not after tonight.
Look, can I come around?
I just wanna--
I got a handyman job
at the royal motel.
They're giving me
a room.
You just
stay right there.
Please, I--I
don't like guns.
What is going on
with you and my son?
He wanted
to help somebody,
Wanted to get somebody
back on their feet,
So he gave me
a little money.
He gave you money?
Yes, ma'am.
That's his savings.
Uh, well,
it's clothes and shoes,
And I got the job
off it.
You think
you can keep it?
Looks to me like
you got yourself
A little problem.
I can lick it.
How's that supposed
to happen all of a sudden?
You ever
been on the street?
My mom took us
pretty close.
Well, you can't know.
Not until you're
looking at a dumpster.
But when you climb
into that thing
For the first time,
And you pull those
newspapers over you,
That's when you know that
you've messed your life up.
Somebody comes along
like your son
And gives me a leg up,
I'll take it.
Even from a kid,
I...
I can't mess up again,
or I'll be dead.
Look, I appreciate what
you're trying to do,
Paying back trevor--
I'm not allowed
to pay back trevor.
Then what is it
you're doing?
I'm paying it forward.
I know
you want me to go.
I'll go.
What's paying it forward?
That's me.
That's me,
and that's 3 people...
And I'm going
to help them,
But it has to be
something really big,
Something they can't
do by themselves...
So I do it for them.
Then they do it
for 3 other people...
That's 9...
And I do 3 more.
That's 27, so, I'm
not really good at math,
But it gets big
really fast, you know?
[all chattering]
It's not gonna work.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
A little articulation,
please.
Yes.
I think
it's a good idea.
Shawn?
It's stupid.
Eugene: Adam?
It's the honor system.
People blow off
the honor system.
So what?
Just 'cause you do.
Eugene: Well, trevor,
the class seems to think
That you've come up with
an overly utopian idea.
Look that word up
in a minute.
Like a perfect world?
Mm-hmm.
So?
So, what put this idea
in your head?
'cause...
Everything sucks.
He talked to you
about this?
We've had
our discussions. Yeah.
But you don't
have to worry, though,
'cause I'll just--
I'll tell him
We can't talk no more.
No, um, don't do that.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
Yes, ma'am.
Ok.
Boy: I call the president,
like, to talk about pollution,
But my mom said now they're
gonna put us on some list,
So she hung up.
[kids laugh]
For this assignment,
I put up recycling flyers
At 2 supermarkets.
I'm gonna put up
this website in chinese
That's gonna tell
all the kids in china
To jump up and down
at the same time.
The goal being to knock
the earth off its axis.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Sit down, shawn.
[laughter]
Well, your ideas
are as surprising
As they are variegated.
Add that
to your list of words
To look up
this evening.
But I want to focus
for a moment
On one project
we heard today,
Because I've been
teaching for many years,
And it really is
the first new idea
That also requires
an extreme act of faith
In the goodness of people.
Trevor has made an attempt
to interact with the world,
And that was the assignment,
And if I were
an effusive person
Given to easy praise,
I would call that...
Admirable.
Now, here are the words
from today.
Utopian, enigma, quantum.
I'm gonna add variegated.
I want you
to go home tonight--
Hey, mr. Simonet.
Hello.
Were you
just being nice?
About what?
About my idea.
Do you think it's good,
or were you just...
Being teachery?
Teachery?
Bullshitting.
Do I strike you
as someone falsely nice?
No. You're not even
really all that nice.
Well, it was a slip-up,
And it will
not happen again.
What?
What happened
to your face?
Did you draw the short
straw today, trevor?
It's not
a very pertinent subject
To social studies,
is it?
You can go back and
tell them that's what I said.
Tell who?
See you tomorrow.
Do you know
where jerry is?
Over there,
at the gate.
[knock on door]
[knocking]
It's more product.
Man: Who is it?
Trevor: It's trevor.
I'm looking for jerry.
Jerry's not here.
Trevor: When
will he be back?
Man: He's not coming back.
Now get outta here.
Jerry?
Man: Get outta here!
Please come out, jerry.
I remember 1976.
There were those programs
In the school system.
Now it's--all that's gone.
Man: I gotta go.
Trevor.
You ran out of class
this morning very fast.
I wanted to talk to you.
[school bell rings]
[knock on door]
Hello.
Come in.
Trevor's not feeling good.
He's in his room.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What's the matter?
Just a tummyache.
Do you want to come in?
Sure.
[clears throat]
Uh, sit down.
Thank you.
It's a very
beautiful home.
Thank you.
Have, uh,
you lived in vegas
Your whole life?
Yeah.
I was surprised
you wanted to do this.
I told him if you
wanted to talk to me,
I would come
to the school.
Mrs. Mckinney,
I didn't ask to see you.
Well,
trevor said you did.
Yeah, and he gave me
a note from you...
Which you didn't write.
He gave you
a note from me?
Oh, god,
that's horrible.
He's been so--
no, I didn't mean you.
Oh, no explanation
required. I'll go.
I didn't mean you.
No, you don't have to--
Hey, it's not personal.
Would you stop?
Can we just rewind here
a little bit?
I obviously didn't realize
how much trevor likes you.
Well, that's nothing
that we can't discuss
On parent-teacher night.
Then why did you come?
Why did you come here?
Why didn't you just tell me
To come to the school?
Because you came
to the school
To talk to me
about your son,
And I behaved
like a...
An asshole?
Sorry. Is that
too trailer trash
A word for you?
How does rat bastard
sit with you?
That's pretty good.
Dickhead?
Oh, I like that.
[laughs]
Look, I'm...
I, um, I made
all this food.
It's just
sittin' here, um...
I really don't know
who else to talk to about him.
Mmm. This is good.
Thanks.
I don't understand.
This is summer school?
Uh-huh.
Why do you think
trevor stopped talking?
I don't know.
He seems mad.
Well, seventh grade
is difficult,
But he seems
very happy at school.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe it's fine.
How much
do you see him?
As much as I can.
How much is that?
No, I'm not doin'
a bunch of skanky guys
Instead of spending time
with my son, ok?
I got 2 jobs.
Right. I meant that.
Couldn't have just
been a question.
Uh, mrs. Mckinney,
do you think
There might
be something,
Um, I don't know,
outside of school
That might
be bothering him?
I don't know.
Ok, you know, I'm
gonna have to consult
My spirit guides here,
because you tell me
That trevor's
withholding from you,
But you won't tell me
anything specific,
And you still
want me to sit here
And divine why.
Divine why?
You always talk like that?
Yes.
You go to some
big, fancy school?
Yes.
Think you could stop
rubbing my nose in it?
Is there a father?
He doesn't
live here anymore.
I don't know
where he is.
Yeah. I know
what that's like.
[knock on door]
Bonnie: Arlene,
I've called you 5 times.
Did you slip or what?
Bonnie.
No, listen,
You don't call your sponsor
once in a while,
You don't
have a sponsor.
Bonnie!
What?
Arlene: This
is eugene simonet.
You're not supposed
to date for a year.
Arlene:
This isn't a date.
No, I'm--I'm
trevor's teacher.
It isn't. It's--
We're having
a conference,
And, uh, we were
through. We're done.
Arlene: We're done.
[sighs]
How could you
do that to me?
Write a letter to him?
Sign my name?
Why'd you have
to mess everything up?
Oh, no.
I didn't mess this up.
What were you doing,
Just standing
at the door
Listening to everything?
What happened
to your stomachache?
What do you care?
You always lie.
Trevor, this
wasn't my fault.
This whole thing
was embarrassing.
I did something good,
and you don't even know it.
Honey, listen.
You can't just put
2 people together
And make 'em
like each other.
It doesn't work
that way.
You only like people
you can get drunk with.
You're just waiting
for him to come back.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
Yes, you are!
No, I'm not!
Your father's
not gettin'
His foot
through--
That's what
you always say.
Well, I mean it now.
You always mean it.
What do you
want me to say?
I say it, I mean it.
I mean it now.
Not when he's around.
When he's around,
You don't care
what happens to me.
You don't ev--
you don't even know
I'm in the same house.
That's not true.
It is true.
You know--
it's true.
Listen, I love you.
I love you.
I'm doing
the best I can.
I don't want you
to love me.
I hate the way you look.
I hate the way you smell.
I hate the way you are.
I hate that
you're my mother.
Trev?
Trev, I'm gonna
come in, ok?
He said that an hour ago.
Do--do you understand
my kid is missing?
If I had a car,
I'd be out looking for him!
[ring]
What time do you
think he took off?
I don't know.
I'm sorry to do this to you.
Bonnie wasn't home,
the cops wouldn't come...
It's ok.
And I would have called
one of my friends,
But my friends
are all drunks...
It's ok.
And so am I.
I'm a drunk, too.
I believe some
people refer to that
As "in recovery."
Where you going?
Hey. You got enough?
You need
a ticket somewhere?
How much? Hmm?
Come with me.
I'll get you there.
I'll get you a ticket,
you son of a bitch.
Honey, are you ok?
Man: Oh! Aah!
Trev, for the rest
of my life,
I could never be as
sorry about anything
As I am for
what I did to you.
I didn't drink.
I wanted to,
but I didn't.
You got no reason
to trust me...
And I know you
don't want to hear
Any more promises,
So I'm just gonna
tell you the truth.
I have a problem.
I have a really bad
problem.
I gotta stop.
And if you can
be with me on this,
If you can think
it's possible
That I can do it...
Then I think
maybe I can...
If you just...
Try a little bit,
and I'll try.
Arlene:
You're still here.
Oh, yeah.
I hope it's ok.
I just wanted
to make sure--
He's asleep.
Good, ok.
How did you know
where he was?
Oh. Well, kids,
they either hitchhike,
Or they take a bus.
Listen, um--
For what?
Well, what?
Wait, give me a shot--
No, you don't have to.
I--I understand--
Wait! God damn,
I want to thank you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
[laughs]
Wasn't quite worth it,
was it?
No.
Listen,
I was wondering,
Do you want to come
back here sometime?
Have dinner with me?
I'm not entirely sure
that would be appropriate.
Ok. I understand.
Good night.
Ok. Why'd you do that man
the favor, sidney?
No, it's, like,
3 favors, player.
You gotta do 3.
Now I'll do
the other 2
Up in here
for my folks.
You know,
a lot of brothers
Need favors in here.
Who told you
to do it?
[sighs]
It's, like,
this idea I got.
Yo, you gonna
put this on tv?
Wait. How did you come up
with an idea like that?
Man, it's like...
It's like the world
is a shit hole.
I mean, excuse my french
and shit, right?
And it's like...
I just thought,
like, boom!
Like the whole shit
could be, like, better.
Didn't start
with anyone else?
No, nigger. That shit
came from here, all right?
The shit came from my head.
I mean, I can't lie
to you, man,
I-I've been through--
Through some
heavy-ass shit...
But not no more, I mean,
'cause it changed me...
And I'm changing
this place, man.
I mean, people
are listening to me.
People are staying clean.
[laughs]
I mean--I mean, it's like
some cosmic aristotle shit.
You feel me?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Yeah, no doubt.
I feel ya.
No doubt, dog.
No doubt.
The thing is,
sidney, um...
Somebody else is saying
that "pay it forward"
Was their idea.
Who?
I think you know who.
That bitch.
No. No. She
a lyin'-ass bitch, man,
I'm telling you.
She's a lyin' bitch.
She got your head.
I'm telling you.
Ok.
Hey, she makes a pretty
good case, though, sid.
That old
crusty bag lady?
I'm telling you, man,
this is all from me,
All from my heart, dog.
Ok. She said--sidney.
What?
Listen to me.
It doesn't matter
If you got it from
the old lady or not,
'cause you're the one
paying it forward.
You damn right.
In prison, no less.
The parole board
will eat that up, sidney.
Oh, the parole board?
The parole board.
[laughs] oh, snap, yo.
You good, man.
Like a little carrot
for the mouse and shit.
[laughs]
no doubt, no doubt.
It's too bad
my parole
Don't come up for
another year, b.
[pounds table with fist]
What if I could make it
So your parole
comes up next month?
Arlene: Hello.
Oh. Hello.
Did you know
I worked here?
No, I didn't.
Really.
So you just dropped in
for a little game of craps?
No. I, uh, I like
the coffee shop.
They--they
have good food.
Yeah. They got
good pancakes.
Yeah. Fluffy.
Do you want me
To bring you
back something?
Oh, no, thanks.
I get off in an hour.
Oh, really?
Yeah, really.
Well--
Well, if you were
gonna eat anyway,
Then,
If you, if you
wanted, maybe,
If you were
hungry, we could--
We could, if you,
if you were,
If you wanted...
Eat something...
Sometime.
7-iron, please.
Yes, sir.
Can I help you?
No, I am not stalking
the governor, jordy.
Shit. Chandler.
You scared me.
You look like crap.
What are you doing out here?
I want to talk
to him, jordan.
Heh! Your questions
piss him off.
Oh, is that why
I got the bounce?
He won't talk to you.
Well, tell him
I'm a candygram.
Stop it.
I got a better idea.
Why don't I tell him
I've been sitting on
a story for 2 years
About a little
party he had.
The cleanup crew
found syringes,
Si 12 1/2
high heels,
Animal droppings.
That can't
be right, can it?
[laughs] if you
really had this,
You'd have used it.
Bullshit.
His friends in high
places had me kill it,
But ever since
I got fired,
I'm really not feeling
that loyal, you know?
What do you want?
$4 million.
[scoffs]
I'm kidding, man.
Relax.
Ha ha ha!
Nothing, man.
A phone call.
I just need
a little phone call.
I need a massage
For a friend of
mine's parole date.
That's it.
God, trevor.
They kept me 40 minutes over.
Did you call him?
I couldn't remember the name
of the stupid restaurant.
I remember the name
of the hotel.
I couldn't remember the n--
He hates people
being late.
If you're late,
he thinks it means
You don't
respect him.
What?
If you're late,
he'll think
It means you
don't respect him.
Well, I don't know.
Are you wearing this?
No. I want to wear
the green dress.
You look like
a vampire in that.
Uhh. I gotta
take a shower.
What?
I smell horrible.
No, you don't.
No, you smell good.
You smell like, uh,
roses or something.
Let me just wash
Under my arms
really quick.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm sure.
Trevor: Oh, wait.
Don't interrupt him
When he's in the middle
of a sentence.
He doesn't
like that, either.
What am I supposed to do,
raise my hand?
Get me my shoes, ok?
No.
Those little sandals.
These.
No, no, no.
I'm not wearing those.
They're way too sexy.
You're too late.
You owe him.
I owe him?
Who are you?
Oh, and none of
those stupid jokes.
He's not that kind
of person, ok?
Thank you
very much.
Where's
the phone?
I gotta call
for a cab.
If I take a bus,
It might be
another hour,
And I'm late.
No. Mom. Mom.
I got a call in
to the cabbie.
I gotta call for a cab.
Duh.
Oh, my god.
You're a champ.
Ok. Ok, mom.
You're
the greatest kid on--
Ok, mom. Ok, mom. Ok.
You have to go.
You have to go, ok?
Oh, here, here, here.
Go. Go.
Lock both doors.
I will.
[arlene talks
to cabdriver]
I love you!
Love you, too, mom.
I respect you!
I respect you.
They kept me
late at work,
And then I got on the bus
to go home and change,
Which was stupid.
That was my fault,
and I'm sorry,
But I was
all the way h--
You're
right on time.
[whispers]
I'm sorry.
[jail cell door bangs]
So I'm, like, living
in vegas, right, man?
And one night,
I was walking
down the street, right?
I'm just minding my own.
Brother wasn't doing
nothing to nobody.
I mean, I was just
on my way to church.
Just out of nowhere, man,
Just--just 5 bloods
just peeled out of a truck,
And one of 'em, man,
was real black.
Hey!
Man, I started
swinging one by one,
Like, nigger, take that.
Ba ba ba ba ba,
Like ali on the bitches,
And I was like what, what,
what, what's up, nigger?
What's up? Bam, bam.
[sirens]
And then all
five of them got up
And started
chasing me, man,
They're like,
"we gonna kill you, bitch.
We gonna kill you, bitch,"
And I was like,
"you can't catch me, blood.
You can't catch me, blood."
Then, man, all of a sudden,
out of nowhere,
That's when I ran
into this old lady.
That's who you want
to know about.
[siren]
[car engine starts]
Man. Uhh!
Aah! Shit.
Hey. You in trouble?
What?
Get in.
Get in?
Come on. Get in.
[sirens]
Sh--
Uhh! [coughs]
[clears throat]
What we doin'?
Whatever we want.
Damn.
Now, you think
I'm going
For your dried-up,
crusty ass? Whatever.
Shoot. I smell better
than you do.
Yeah. All right.
All right. So, what?
What you want?
Don't matter,
'cause you ain't
gonna do it.
You're damn right
about that. [laughs]
Shit.
Hey, not in my car.
Oh, hey, hey, hey, shit.
Not in my car. [laughs]
Oh, my--my--my bad,
my bad.
This is like
your pad, right?
You don't want me--
you don't want me
To jack up all
your pretty curtains.
Oh, son of a bitch.
I paid it forward
For a hophead
son of a bitch.
[coughs] you--you paid--
you paid what?
I didn't hear that.
I ain't gonna tell you,
'cause your ass ain't
good enough to touch it.
[quietly] oh, my ass
ain't good enough, huh?
Now, you gonna tell me.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
♪ you gonna tell me ♪
Chris: Let me
just get this straight.
Some old bat that lives
in her car in las vegas
Tells you about
pay it forward.
No. She didn't
want to, man,
But, you know,
a brother wouldn't stop
Until she let it out.
Well, what I want
to know, sidney,
What I really want
to know is why?
Why did you
pay it forward?
Because
don't nobody tell me
What I can
and can't touch, yo.
[go-kart motor roars]
Bonnie: How many times
have I told you
You're not supposed
to date for a year.
They're not dates.
Oh, ok. 7 dinners.
What are they?
No. It's a couple
of adults
Sitting down--
and dating.
No.
Did he pay?
He pays for everything.
Trevor, did
anybody ask you?
He's new. He doesn't
know that many people.
He likes her.
So?
He fixed
your tv remote.
Oh, that's
an engagement ring.
And he
doesn't drink.
Do you gotta pee?
Look.
I need a smoke.
There. Over there.
So, has he kissed you?
No, no, no, no, no.
[laughs]
Does he want to?
Sometimes
I think he does.
He can't really want to,
or he would have.
Do you want him to?
[engine starts]
Arlene: I don't know.
Whoo!
Shit, bonnie.
It's just taking forever.
Haven't you ever
gotten to know somebody
Before you
went to bed with him?
Is that d?
Bonnie: It's pathetic.
[laughs]
[dogs barking]
Well, good night.
Um...
Do you want
to come in
And...Stay?
I...
Come in.
Trevor's
inside the house.
He sleeps
like the dead.
I don't
want to make it
Any harder for you.
Well,
You're supposed
to wait a year.
Isn't that what
bonnie said to you?
Ok.
I...
I can't.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
No. I don't mean
I can't.
It's just...
What?
It's complicated.
I get it.
It's ok to say
you don't like me that way.
Is that what
you think it is?
It's ok.
Arlene.
How could you
ever think that?
What?
What is it?
[engine starts]
And you're
doing this because...
I need more links.
You're spending $300
to go to vegas
And find an old lady
So you can sell
a story for $300.
It's a news magazine
feature, rochelle.
All right?
It's not something
you wipe your ass with.
You have such a lovely way
of expressing yourself.
Hey, do me a favor.
Don't change
the locks on me, ok?
Hmm.
[kisses]
Chris, what are you
hoping this'll be?
Just, you know,
Something that
clears a check.
You know?
Are you sure that's all?
Look. Ok. I, uh, I drank
the last of the coffee.
Please put it
on the list.
Huh.
[kisses]
Bye.
[music playing]
♪ if some miracle ♪
♪ could win your love
for me ♪
♪ whoa, little girl ♪
♪ how happy I would be ♪
[knock on door]
♪ if some miracle could
win your love for me ♪
[knocks]
Who's there?
♪ win your love ♪
♪ your love for me ♪
Hey.
Do you
look down on me?
What?
Do you
look down on me?
No.
'cause I don't
talk like you.
I haven't read
the stuff you read.
What are you
talking about?
That's not pertinent,
and you know it.
Don't talk to me
like that.
I'm sorry, but that's
the way I talk, you know.
Words are all I have.
Why? Why?
'cause you think
you look like shit?
Is that it?
I don't care about
your burns, eugene,
If that's
even what they are.
Is that
what they are?
Yes.
Ok. Well, whatever
happened to you,
You look good to me.
You look good
to me, too.
Ok. So?
So I've never
been here before.
Ok.
So you're scared.
I'm scared, too.
Listen.
Bad things have
happened to me, ok?
I can't take
my shirt off with a guy
Without 5 beers in me,
But I want that
with you.
More than I'm scared,
I want that.
♪ win your love for me ♪
♪ for me ♪
♪ whoa ♪
[music stops]
You don't see me.
All right, my life--
My life is familiar,
My life is--
It's manageable.
Every day...
I have a thing
I do every day.
It's all
I've ever known.
And...
It's a routine,
And as long
as I have that--
As long
I'm ok, I'm ok.
If I don't have it,
I'm lost.
So is that
all you want?
Your god damn
manageable day?
It's what I have.
No, it isn't.
Is it what you want?
Yes!
It's what I want!
I don't believe you.
Ok. That's
the best I got.
It's not about you--
Yes, it is!
Something's been
offered to you here,
And you
don't want it.
Maybe you're scared
to get rejected.
Well, I can't
reject you.
You're too quick
for me!
[door slams]
Hey.
You didn't call me
a fag, did you?
Hey, look
what I found!
What do you want?!
Give me that!
It's
my asthma spray!
Shut up!
Adam: Stop it!
Stay still!
Stop! Help me!
Hold still!
Hey!
Hey, mckinney.
Come here.
Boy: Yeah,
let's hang out.
Help me. Please.
Screw it.
He's not doing anything.
Come on.
Let me go!
Trevor...
You cut my class.
It's been 4 days.
What's been 4 days?
Why haven't you
called my mother?
It's been 4 days.
I don't know.
Neither does she.
Hey,
what's the matter?
Pay it forward
didn't work.
I couldn't
even do it.
I was gonna
help adam.
Help adam do what?
Not get beat up.
But I crapped out,
and I let him.
I let him get beat.
No, you didn't.
You didn't let him get beat.
It just--it--
it happens, you know?
Trevor, sometimes
there's nothing we can do.
It's not fair.
I know--
no!
You don't know.
You should call
my mother.
You could do
something
If you wanted.
Why are you
so chicken?
Trevor, I'm not chicken--
Something's
gonna happen.
Then it'll
be too late.
What's gonna happen?
What do you mean?
He'll come back.
Who will come back?
Hey, who will come--
Your dad.
Your dad will come back?
And...
What will happen
When he comes back,
trevor?
Will he hurt you?
Will he hurt her?
Not if
someone's there...
Instead of him.
[whispering] trevor...
Trevor, it's--
It's complicated
for me now. I...
Is the world
just shit?
No, it isn't.
Hey.
You did good work.
Look at me.
I'm proud of you, trevor.
I'm proud of you.
And anyway,
for what it's worth,
I'm grading you
on the effort,
Not the result.
I don't care
about the grade.
I just wanted to see
If the world
would really change.
[knock on door]
Hi.
Uh, come in.
Ohh! Trevor!
It worked!
Oh, god!
Eugene: Does he always
get up this early?
What?
Oh, my god,
this is not good.
He just saw me!
It's ok!
Now you have to
pay it forward, too!
Trevor: Eugene?
I think you should
Still call me
mr. Simonet.
You had a sleepover,
didn't you?
Why don't you
go back to bed?
Why?
It's too early
for you to be up--
No, it's not early!
No, it's a Sunday!
It's a Sunday?
Yeah.
So stay, stay!
You don't
understand,
I have
a whole schedule
That you don't
know about.
All right, well,
bring everything here!
Would you please
take care of him?
I'll call you later,
all right?
Don't be a stranger!
God, trevor!
Trevor: Do you like him?
Ok.
[woman sobbing]
Hey! Hey, hey!
Lady, come on.
Go away.
I-I'm not
gonna hurt you, lady.
Oh, here, take it!
Well, it's
a nice thought,
But it's not
what I want.
What--what--
Hey, what
are you doing?
I'm not
gonna hurt you!
What are you--hey!
Oh, my god!
Listen to me.
Nothing's
this important!
Come on, come--
come down here!
What are you doing?
Woman: What do
you care, anyway?
Because I owe
somebody a favor.
Not me.
Why not you?
You know--heh!
A minute ago,
All I could
think about
Was getting
my next fix,
And then I saw you,
a-and...
I changed
my thinking.
Oh, please!
Go away!
Trust me,
I'm not worth it.
Why's that?
Oh, for god's sake!
Come on, tell me!
Why are you
not worth it?
Trust me...
You wouldn't understand.
Are you kidding me?
You think
I live at the ritz?
Have a cup of coffee
with me?
What?
Do me a favor.
Save my life.
[shouting]
Get him! Get him!
Off the ropes!
Oh, he missed him.
Oh, oh, oh, yeah, he did!
Bam-ba-bam-ba-bam-ba-bam!
Oh, oh, come on,
bleed, dude.
Announcer: Distraction
from the imperial...
Oh, he's got him.
Give the ddt!
What?
It's gonna
be a ddt.
Up he goes,
and drop him on his head!
Oh, he's dead.
He's dead.
Ok, fearless,
get out of the ring.
What do you mean,
get out of the ring?
You can't get
out of t ring.
Yes, he can.
He has to get a chair.
A chair?
[whispering]
Bam!
Aah!
Slow motion.
Hyah!
Trevor, when did you
become so violent?
Oh, no, no, no.
Take me to a match.
You get splattered
in the front row.
I don't want to be
splattered, thank you--
Yes, you do.
It'll be, like,
Your birthday
present to me.
Oh, no. You know what you're
getting for your birthday?
What?
A brand-new encyclopedia...
Oh, ohh.
Leather-bound...
Thucydides' history
of the peloponnesian war.
No, I'm getting you
51 crackling volumes.
There'll be
pop quizzes every day
On the development
of cotton farms--
Hi, arlene.
Unh!
You can't
stay here, ricky.
I know.
Look, I know
what we had
Was a nightmare,
arlene,
But I did it.
You did what?
I knew I
couldn't come back
To this house
unless I was sober.
It's the truth.
5 months,
2 weeks, and 4 days
Of the truth.
[clears throat]
Where you been?
What does it
matter?
I knew
I had to change.
Are you sober?
Yeah, and I got sober
staying right here.
Well, you're
stronger than me.
Can you just stop
for a minute...
Please?
Can we just
sit down and talk?
Ok.
[sighs]
Hi.
God!
I'm sorry.
What are you
doing here?
I want you
to understand--
Oh, it's not
necessary, really.
No explanation
required.
Please don't talk
to me like that.
We had 13 years in,
eugene.
He's sober now.
We've never been
sober together.
Well,
I wish you luck.
I feel like I gotta
give him a chance.
A chance?
A chance
for what?
To change,
To try to make up
for lost time.
Oh, what, to take trevor
to some ball games?
Do some real daddy
things with him?
Yeah.
He promised
to try.
What do you
want me to do?
Oh, I don't know,
be smart.
He's his father,
eugene.
He impregnated you,
arlene.
In what other way has he
been a father to trevor?
Unless knocking somebody
around is a new family value.
What are you
talking about?
He never
touched trevor.
Oh, that's right.
Only you.
He only took it
out on you.
That's so much better.
What did trevor
tell you?
Enough.
Christ, arlene. Secrets
like that shouldn't be kept.
What good
does it do trevor?
You weren't there.
Ricky never meant to hit me.
We were drunk--
Christ! What is it
with women like you?
Is that something you
really tell yourself?
"oh, it's ok he beat me.
Trevor's ok"?
Trevor has locked
himself in a bathroom,
And he can't breathe,
And he's--and he's
hoping and praying
That it will stop.
Trevor never
went through--
How do you know what
trevor went through?
How do you know?
How do you know that
next time after you,
He doesn't
come for trevor?
I know what I'm
talking about, arlene.
My father
got on his knees
And begged
my mother,
And my mother,
She always
took him back.
I never understood it.
She covered the bruises
and the cuts,
And she'd take him back
Because he begged
And he cried.
And now you ask me
what happened
After he came back.
No--
no, go on!
You said
you wanted to know
What happened to me.
Now ask me.
I don't like this.
Did he hurt you,
eugene? Ask me!
Did he hurt you?
Not for long.
By 13, I was gone.
I ran away...
But I missed her,
So I had to go back
and see her.
And so one night, I did.
Now ask me what
happened that night.
What happened that night
you came back, eugene?
What happened?
He was there...
Drunk as usual.
Only this time,
I wasn't the same.
I was 16 years old,
And I was no longer
afraid of him.
And when I looked
him in the eye
And told him if he
ever touched her again
I would kill him,
He knew...
He knew that
he would never exist
For me again.
And I'm standing
in front of the house.
I'm telling her,
I'm screaming
for her to come out.
I'm telling her
she doesn't have to--
She doesn't have
to take it anymore.
She really doesn't.
She can come
with me now.
I don't even
see it coming.
He hits me in
the side of the head
With a 2x4,
And I'm bleeding
from my ear.
And then
he's dragging me.
He's dragging me
behind the house
And into the garage,
and then he's gone.
A minute, 5 minutes,
I don't know.
And then he's back, and
he's wetting me down.
He's wetting me down,
and I don't understand.
I don't understand
why water...
Should smell so bad.
I don't understand.
And then I see it.
I see...
This...
This gas can,
This red gas can
from his trunk.
And he looks at me
one last time...
And he lights a match.
And the last thing
I remember...
And I'll never
forget it...
Were his eyes.
His eyes because they
were filled with this...
Immense...
Satisfaction.
I'm so sorry--
Don't--don't--don't tell me
how sorry you are for me!
Just tell me how
you're gonna stop it
Happening to trevor.
Ricky would
never do that.
Oh, jesus, arlene.
He doesn't have to.
All he has to do
is not love him.
[door closes]
[honking horn]
Jesus!
[radio playing
papa roach's last resort]
♪ this is my last resort ♪
Hey.
♪ cut my life
into pieces-- ♪
What's going on?
What are you doing?
What's it look
like I'm doing?
What are you putting
in my room?
We had an agreement.
My son won't
talk to me.
He won't even
look at me!
What the hell
did you do
To turn him
against me?
I didn't do anything.
I told you I wasn't gonna
make him talk to you.
You could go
get a job.
What am I supposed
to use for a car?
The bus.
That's what I do.
Yeah, that'll
be the day.
Ricky, you can't
stay in this room.
Look, this is
our room, baby.
Ok, this is our house.
This is our bed--
You've been drinking.
Kiss me.
Stop it.
Stop it. Stop it.
♪ I never realized
I was spread too thin ♪
[louder]
♪ till it was too late ♪
♪ and I was empty within-- ♪
I want you out.
♪ downward spiral ♪
♪ where do I begin? ♪
Turn that noise down!
I'm gonna come in there
and pound your ass, boy!
Don't talk to him
like that.
[music stops]
I've had enough of
this shit around here.
Yeah, what are you
gonna do?
Get out!
You know, I like you
a whole lot better
When you had
a few drinks in you.
[pounds on door]
You want me out
of the house? I'm out.
Sorry.
I think
I made a mistake.
Everybody
makes mistakes.
[door slams]
♪ please open your window ♪
♪ hold me
in that lap tonight ♪
♪ no matter which way
the wind blows ♪
♪ let your heart
out to ride ♪
♪ I've put all
the care and woe ♪
♪ in the world
down below ♪
♪ just open your window ♪
♪ and you know where to go ♪
I was wonderin' if
you could help me out.
[school bell rings]
All right,
bring them up.
Thank you.
Carefully.
Thank you. Careful. Did you
get rid of your hiccups?
Girl: Yes.
Good.
I told you holding
your breath would work.
Thank you.
Careful. Thank you.
Thanks.
That's very nice.
Give me that one.
Thank you.
Trevor, what is it?
Are you still gonna
pay it forward?
You could say
you don't have to.
'cause it
didn't work out.
But I thought
you still might.
Trevor, I would like
more than anything
To do that for you.
And when I find
something worthy of--
I know somebody
who needs something.
Trevor, you have to let
me find this on my own.
You know who it is.
Look...
You don't understand
everything, all right?
So you do not know
what you're asking.
Give her
another chance.
I will pay it forward,
I promise you that...
But I cannot do that.
But that's why
this is the one...
Because it's
supposed to be
Something hard.
If you hp my mom,
Even if you're
still mad at her,
If you helped her
in a way
Nobody else could--
Did she ask you
to come talk to me--
No. She thinks you'll
never forgive her,
But I still think
you could.
If you wanted to do
something really huge...
For someone...
For my project...
For me.
Trevor,
she made her choice.
She said
she made a mistake.
Well, that's
the beauty of hindsight.
You don't care.
Yes, I do.
I will always care.
About you, always.
Yeah.
You're my teacher.
They pay you to.
You got it?
Yeah, yeah, uh-huh.
I ain't saying a thing
till I get one more.
You know...
I thought you might
feel that way.
Uh-uh, no, no. Later.
I got my places,
Places...
Where nobody cares where
you park overnight.
Places where I live.
Anybody who knows me
knows where to find me.
Hi, mom.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to see you.
After 3 years--
I couldn't--I can't
watch you do this.
I drive by
your house.
I know.
He's big.
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
Are--are you...
Are you gonna try
to put me somewhere?
No.
Then what do you want?
I want to try
to do something.
All the things...
When I was a kid...
The booze...
And the men.
What happened to me
When you
weren't looking.
I know
we're all weak.
Oh, not you--
No, I've been weak.
Well...
Here's the thing.
I forgive you.
Oh...
I don't like
your hair--
I know. I'm not
putting it back.
So, I'd like to
see you sometimes.
Is that ok?
Yes.
You can't
live with me?
No.
I wouldn't want to.
Ha ha.
Can I see him?
Not drunk.
You gotta be sober,
Even if it's
just for 2 hours.
Yeah, I can do that.
Ok.
Well, then I'll
come and find you.
Ok?
Yeah.
Ok.
Why'd you
do this, arley?
So, she told me why.
She told me I had
to do something big...
For 3 other people.
♪ happy birthday,
dear trevor ♪
♪ happy birthday to you ♪
♪ and many more ♪
[cheering and applause]
What'd you wish for?
He can't tell you
what he wished for,
Or it won't come true.
Can I have some napkins?
Who wants a big--
where's my knife?
[knock on door]
I'll get it.
Mom?
Hello.
Hi. Mrs. Mckinney,
I'm chris chandler.
I'm a reporter.
I was wondering
If I could have
a moment of your time.
Why?
I don't have anything
to say about anything.
Please, I've already
spoken to your mother,
Which naturally
led me to you, so...
My mother?
She told me about
The pay it forward
idea
And how you've
helped her out,
And I'm doing
a story about it.
No, no, you can't.
That's private.
Ok, mrs. Mckinney--
My son's upset
about it.
It was
a social studies thing,
And it didn't work out
the way he wanted it to.
Social studies?
Yeah. Please
just leave it alone.
He just wants to get on
with the seventh grade.
Seventh grade?
How do you--
Plus it's his birthday party,
and it's a bad time, ok?
I'm sorry to--
No, I'm sorry,
mrs. Mckinney.
I've been
tracking this story
From los angeles, ok?
Pay it forward,
the movement--
It's reached l.A.,
mrs. Mckinney.
Come on, the movement?
Yeah. You're
telling me your son
Had something
to do with this?
Aah!
[imitates crash]
We really appreciate
this, ms. Mckinney.
It's up to him.
Good.
Ready, slugger?
I guess.
There you go.
Up here, please, sir.
Just like you're
getting a haircut.
You ever been
interviewed before?
No.
Hey, trevor.
This is for you.
Hi. How are you?
What's your name?
Chris chandler.
Nice to meet you.
A little less painful
than a trip to the dentist.
You're gonna be great.
Just be yourself, ok, pal?
Ok.
You ready to go?
I guess.
You guess?
Come on, you gotta
have some gusto here.
Are we ready?
All right, let's go.
All right, great.
Ok, now, just be
yourself. Relax.
It's gonna be
a lot of fun, ok?
All right.
Ok, we're on?
Hi, I'm chris chandler,
and I'm joined today
By a very unusual
seventh grader,
Trevor mckinney.
Trevor,
you must be
Pretty proud
of yourself.
No.
So you're not
proud at all?
I don't know.
I guess.
Come on,
you start a movement
Like pay it forward.
You're not proud?
I guess. I mean, I got
an "a" in social studies,
But that was
just for the effort.
I mean, the stuff I did
didn't really work out.
You're here.
Yeah, but...
I don't know.
I tried real hard,
But nothing
really happened.
My mom's stuff
worked.
She talked
to my grandma,
Kind of made up
with her,
And it was
really hard for her.
It was great for me,
Because my grandma came
to my birthday party,
And I had
really missed her.
And that's why
pay it forward
Went to all
those places...
'cause of my mom.
'cause
she was so brave.
My stuff,
I--I don't know.
I think some people are
too scared or something.
I think things
can be different...
And, I mean,
the world's--
The world's
not exactly...
Shit.
But I guess it's hard
for some people
Who are so used to things
the way they are--
Even if they're bad--
To change...
And they kind of give up.
When they do,
everybody kind of...
Kind of loses.
Arlene...
I don't want to be
one of those people
He's talking about,
And I've become one.
I don't want
to spend
Another second
of wasted air.
Please don't let me stay
trapped in here forever.
I won't.
I don't
want to spend
Another second
without you.
Girl: Trevor,
that was awesome.
See you later, guys.
Boy: Tomorrow, right?
Bye, man.
Let me go!
Stop it!
Who'd you tell?
Who'd you tell,
tattletale?
I didn't tell anybody.
Ah, ah, ah!
I swear I didn't
say anything!
Help!
Let me go.
Stop it.
Trevor!
Come here.
Eugene: Hey!
Let me go!
Trevor!
No, trevor! Hey!
Get out of my face!
Punch him. Come on!
No!
Eugene: Leave him alone!
Trevor!
Trevor?
Unh!
Trevor?!
Someone get
an ambulance!
Trevor: But I guess it's hard
for some people who are...
So used to things
the way they are--
Even if they're bad--
to change...
Because...
I guess they kinda give up.
And when they do...
Everybody kinda loses.
Newsman: These moments
make you sorry
To have to report
anything at all.
This remarkable young man
died at 7:35 this evening.
Newswoman: There are
now confirmed incidents
Of pay it forward
In los angeles,
san francisco.
And in phoenix,
we're checking to see
If the 16
foster children
Who just received
computers
Is in any way connected
to this movement.
Trevor: It's hard.
You can't plan it.
You have to watch people
more, you know,
Sort of...
Sort of keep an eye on 'em
To protect 'em, because...
They can't always
see what they need.
It's--it's like
your big chance
To fix something
that's not like your bike.
You can...Fix a person.
Chris: Is that what
you want for your birthday,
Everybody
to pay it forward?
I can't ask for that.
Sure, you can.
Why not?
Wouldn't work.
Why?
I already
blew out my candles.
[ © anoXmous @ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous/]